Guide to the Elizabeth Bishop Papers, circa 1880-2023 (bulk 1929-1979)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
- SERIES V. POETRY
  - Unpublished poetry
    - Prince (Winston) Mannerly, [1934]; (TS, 1 draft, 3 p.) (Folder 64.4)
    - Poem from 1935, (TS, 1 draft, 1 p.) (Folder 64.5)
    - In a Room, [1936]; (MS, TS, miscellaneous drafts, 6 p.) (Folder 64.6)
    - The Soldier and the Slot Machine, [1942]; (TS, 1 draft, 2 p.) (Folder 64.7)
    - After the Rain, [1942]; (MS, 1 draft, 1 p.) (Folder 64.8)
    - Full Moon, Key West, [1943]; (TS, 1 draft, 1 p.) (Folder 64.9)
    - The Owl's Journey, [1949-1950]; (MS, TS, 3 drafts, 4 p. with drawing of owl on rabbit's back) (Folder 64.10)
    - Establishment of a Community in Brazil, [1949-1950]; (MS, 1 draft, fragment, 2 p.) (Folder 64.11)
    - Voyages Antibes and Antibes Way, [1949-1950]; (TS, 1 draft, 1 p.) (Folder 64.12)
    - Verdigris [rejected by New Yorker, 1/20/50], [approximately 1949]; (TS, 1 draft, fragment, 2 p.) (Folder 64.13)
    - Desk at Night (Little Exercise?) [basis for "12 O'Clock News"], [1950]; (MS, TS, 3 drafts, fragment, 4 p.) (Folder 64.14)
    - Mimoso, Near Death, [1959]; (TS, miscellaneous drafts, 3 p.) (Folder 64.15)
    - Brasil, 1959, [approximately 1959]; (MS, TS, 1 draft, 2 p.) (Folder 64.16)
    - To the Brook Below the Window, [approximately 1961-1962]; (MS, miscellaneous drafts, 4 p.) (Folder 64.17)
    - Utacamud, [1969]; (MS, TS, 2 drafts 2 p.) (Folder 64.18)
    - Apartment in Copacabana, [1960s?]; (MS, TS, miscellaneous drafts, 30 p.) (Folder 64.19)
    - Elegy/Aubade and Elegy, [1970s]; (TS, 4 drafts, 4 p.) (Folder 64.20)
    - Leda and the/a Duck, [1970]; (MS, 2 drafts, 2 p.) (Folder 64.21)
    - Poem for Alice Methfessel for her birthday, [1971 Feb]; (1 torn TS) (Folder 121.5)
    - A Drunkard, [1971]; (TS, 1 draft, 2 p.) (Folder 64.22)
    - [Untitled ("It moved aerial...")] (by O. Paz, translated by E. Bishop), 1972 Feb; (MS, TS, 2 drafts, 5 p.) (Folder 64.23)
    - Florida Revisited, [mid-1970s?]; (MS, TS, miscellaneous drafts, 3 p.) (Folder 64.24)
    - Maithuna (by O. Paz, translated by E. Bishop), [1979?]; (MS, TS, 2 drafts, 5 p.) (Folder 65.1)
    - Near Cape Gomorin (by O. Paz, translated by E. Bishop), [1979?]; (TS, 4 drafts, 6 p.) (Folder 65.2)
    - Tomb of Amir Khusru (by O. Paz, translated by E. Bishop), [1979?]; (TS, 2 drafts, 2 p.) (Folder 65.3)
    - Aboard the "Prince Fundy,", undated; (MS, TS, 4 drafts, 4 p.) (Folder 65.4)
    - Aboard the "Prince Fundy,", undated; (1 MS in Kirkland House stationery) (Folder 121.6)
    - All Afternoon the Freighters (Rio), undated; (TS, MS, miscellaneous drafts, 11 p.) (Folder 65.5)
    - Asylum, undated; (MS, miscellaneous drafts, 11 p.) (Folder 65.6)
    - The Bees, undated; (MS, 1 draft, 2p.) (Folder 65.7)
    - Belated Dedication, undated; (TS, 1 draft, 1 p.) (Folder 65.8)
    - Bicycles, undated; (TS, 1 draft, 1 p.) (Folder 65.9)
    - Capricorn, undated; (TS, 1 draft, 1 p.) (Folder 65.10)
    - City Stars, undated; (TS, 1 draft, 1 p.) (Folder 65.11)
    - Cochin/Sunyata/Aptheosis of a Duplex, undated; (MS, TS, 2 drafts, 2 p.) (Folder 65.12)
    - Crossing the Equator, undated; (MS, 1 draft, 2 p.) (Folder 65.13)
    - Death By Exposure, undated; (TS, 3 drafts, 3 p.) (Folder 65.14)
    - An Evening/Apotheosis of a Duplex, undated; (TS, 1 draft, 1p.) (Folder 65.15)
    - [First] Syllables, undated; (MS, miscellaneous drafts, 4 p.) (Folder 65.16)
    - Florida (Going to Florida?), undated; (MS, 1 draft, 1 p.) (Folder 65.17)
    - For a Pair of Eyebrows, undated; (TS, 1 p.) (Folder 65.18)
    - For Grandfather, undated; (TS, 4 p.) (Folder 65.19)
    - For T.C.B., undated; (TS, 1 draft, 1 p.) (Folder 65.20)
    - The Fortunate Traveler, undated; (MS, 1 draft, 1 p.) (Folder 65.21)
    - [Four poems attributed to Elizabeth Bishop: Day Dream; Adamant; You; Sonnet], undated; (MS, 3 p.) (Folder 66.1)
    - Leaving Rio or Almost Any Seaport (From the City to the Country), undated; (MS, 1 draft, 1 p.) (Folder 66.2)
    - Full Moon, undated; (MS, 1 draft, 1 p.) (Folder 66.3)
    - Giant Snail [See verso of last draft of Sammy, Folder 67.8], undated; (fragment of draft, TS, 1 p.) (Folder 67.8)
    - [The] Grandmother, undated; (MS, TS, miscellaneous drafts, 3 p.) (Folder 66.4)
    - Gypsophilia, undated; (TS, early drafts, fragment, 6 p.) (Folder 66.5)
    - Hannah A., undated; (MS, miscellaneous drafts, 6 p.) (Folder 66.6)
    - Happy Birthday [for Magú], undated; (TS, 1 p.) (Folder 113.12)
    - The Happy Man, undated; (MS, 2 drafts, 4 p.) (Folder 66.7)
    - House Decoration in Nubia, undated; (TS, 1 draft, 1 p.) (Folder 66.8)
    - In the Sleeping Wood [translation of Paul Valéry's "Au Bois Dormant"], undated; (MS, 2 draft, 2 p.) (Folder 127.12)
      Removed from Bishop's copy of Valéry's Poésies,
      Grille PQ 2643.A26 P61933
    - Inventory, undated; (TS, 1 draft, 1 p.) (Folder 66.9)
    - Just North of Boston, undated; (TS, 2 drafts, 2 p.) (Folder 66.10)
    - Keaton, undated; (TS, 1 draft, 1 p.) (Folder 66.11)
    - Key West, undated; (MS, 1 draft, 2 p.) (Folder 66.12)
    - Last Summer's Dream, undated; (MS, 1 draft, 4 p.) (Folder 66.13)
    - Letter to Two Friends (A Letter Home) (Letter Back), undated; (TS, 1 draft, 1 p.) (Folder 66.14)
    - Little Thaw in January, undated; (MS, 1 draft, 5 p.) (Folder 66.15)
    - The Man on the Raft, undated; (MS, 1 draft, 1 p.) (Folder 66.16)
    - Memory of Baltimore (A Vision of Baltimore), undated; (TS, 1 draft, 1 p.) (Folder 66.17)
    - [Miscellaneous translations], undated; (TS, MS, 4 p.) (Folder 66.18)
    - Mimosas in Bloom, undated; (TS, 1 draft, 1 p.) (Folder 66.19)
    - The Monument to Don Pedro II, Petropolis, undated; (MS, 1 draft, 1 p.) (Folder 66.20)
    - The Mouse, or Life in a Hotel, undated; (MS, 1 draft, 2 p.) (Folder 67.1)
    - Newsreel, undated; (MS, TS, miscellaneous 6 p.) (Folder 67.2)
    - On the Amazon, undated; (TS, 1 draft, 1 p.) (Folder 67.3)
    - The Pretender, undated; (TS, miscellaneous drafts, 2 p.) (Folder 67.4)
    - Real Estate Development 6 A.M., undated; (MS, miscellaneous drafts, 9 p.) (Folder 67.5)
    - St. John's Day, undated; (TS, 1 draft, 1 p.)) (Folder 67.6)
    - Salem Willows, undated; (MS, TS, 14 p. (Folder 67.7)
    - Sammy [on verso of last draft is a draft of Giant Snail], undated; (TS, miscellaneous drafts, 4 p.) (Folder 67.8)
    - Santos Dumont, undated; (TS, 1 draft, 1 p. miscellaneous drafts, 14 p.) (Folder 67.9)
    - Semi-Private Room, undated; (TS, 1 draft, 1 p.) (Folder 67.10)
    - Sled Poem, undated; (MS, 1 draft, 1 p.) (Folder 67.11)
    - Something I've Meant To Write About for 30 Years, undated; (TS, 1 draft, 1 p.) (Folder 67.12)
    - Stoves and Clocks, undated; (MS, miscellaneous drafts, 4 p.) (Folder 67.13)
    - Suicide of a Moderate Dictator (For Carlos Lacerda) (August 24th, Rio de Janeiro), undated; (MS, TS, 6 drafts, 7 p.) (Folder 67.14)
    - Talking, undated; (TS, 1 draft, 1 p.) (Folder 67.15)
    - The Tin Can, undated; (TS, 1 draft, 1 p.) (Folder 67.16)
    - To Manuel Bandeira, With a Present, undated; (TS, 3 drafts, 3 p.) (Folder 67.17)
    - To the Admirable Miss Moore, undated; (MS, 1 draft, 1 p.) (Folder 67.18)
    - Travelling, a Love Poem, undated; (MS, TS, 3 drafts, 3 p.) (Folder 67.19)
    - A Trip to the Mines – Brazil, undated; (TS, 2 drafts, 3 p.) (Folder 67.20)
    - Ungracious Poem, undated; (TS, 2 drafts, 3 p.) (Folder 67.21)
    - [Untitled: (first line) "The Mail was fifteen minutes early..."], undated; (TS, miscellaneous drafts, 6 p.) (Folder 67.22)
    - Vague Poem, undated; (TS, 2 drafts, 2 p.) (Folder 67.23)
    - Young Man in the Park, undated; (TS, 1 draft, 1 p.) (Folder 67.24)
- SERIES VI. FRAGMENTS
  - Fragments. Poetry and Prose, undated; (TS, MS, 34 p.) (Folder 68.1)
  - Fragments. Poetry and Prose, undated; (TS, MS, 28 p. [27 originals and 1 photocopy]) (Folder 68.2)
  - Fragments. Poetry and Prose, undated; (TS, MS, 65 p.) (Folder 68.3)
  - Fragments. Poetry and Prose, undated; (TS, MS, 39 p.) (Folder 68.4)
  - Fragments. Prose, undated; (TS, MS, 34 p.) (Folder 68.5)
  - Poem fragment: "I feel things very slowly...", undated; (1 TS) (Folder 121.7)
  - Poem fragment: "Geography III" written at the top, undated; (1 MS on a torn Harvard envelope) (Folder 121.8)
- SERIES VII. NOTES AND NOTEBOOKS
  - High school and college notes, notebooks, and themes
    - High School Theme: "Elizabethan Music,", [1928 Oct]; (MS, 6 p.) (Folder 69.1)
    - College notes: Eng. 165: Shakespeare, Vassar College, [1930-1931]; (MS, 20 p.) (Folder 69.2)
    - College notes: Eng. 255: English Drama, Vassar College [taught by Swenarton], [1931]; (MS, 22 p.) (Folder 69.3)
    - College notes: [probably Zoology 105: Animal Biology], Vassar College, [1931]; (MS, 2 p.) (Folder 69.4)
    - College notes: Greek 310a: Euripides, Vassar College [taught by Macurdy], [1932]; (MS, 13 p.) (Folder 69.5)
    - College notes: Poetry, Vassar College, [1932?]; (MS, 2 p.) (Folder 69.6)
    - College notes: [Eng. 255?] Drama Course, Vassar College, [1931-1932]; (MS, 36 p.) (Folder 69.7)
    - College Notes: Bibliography 190: Bibliography, Vassar College [taught by Dorothy Plum], [1932-1933]; (MS, 37 p.) (Folder 69.8)
    - College notes: Music 140: Music as a Literature, Vassar College, [1932-1933]; (MS, 78 p.) (Folder 69.9)
    - College notes: American Literature, [probably Eng. 325], Vassar College, [1933-1934]; (MS, 8 p.) (Folder 69.10)
    - College notes: Literary Critical Theory, [probably Eng. 480: Studies in Critical Theory],Vassar College, [1933-1934]; (MS, 65 p.) (Folder 69.11)
    - College notes: English Literature, Vassar College, [1933?-1934?]; (MS, 79 p.) (Folder 69.12)
    - College notes: English Literature, Vassar College, undated; (MS, 52 p.) (Folder 70.1)
    - Miscellaneous Notes, Vassar College, undated; (MS, 5 p.) (Folder 70.2)
    - Miscellaneous Notes, Vassar College, undated; (MS, 9 p.) (Folder 70.3)
    - [College notes?] Vidal VII. MS. BN fr. F64d' 2254, undated; (MS, 1 p.) (Folder 70.4)
    - Baccalaureate Hymn, 1934; (Ditto sheet, 1 p.) (Folder 70.5)
    - College theme: "'The Noble Savage"? Vassar - '32?"', [1932?]; (TS, 19 p.) (Folder 70.6)
    - College theme: "Butler's Theory of Heredity as Illustrated in The Way of All Flesh, [1933 Apr]; (MS, 6 p.) (Folder 70.7)
    - College theme: "Assisted by the Holy Author" [essay on Cotton Mather, written for course taught by Amy Reed (Eng. 325: Amer. Lit.?)], [1933-1934]; (MS, TS, 19 p.) (Folder 70.8)
    - College theme: "Dimensions for a Novel" [Eng. 350: Contemporary Prose Fiction, taught by R. Peebles; published in Vassar Journal of Undergraduate Studies, May 1934], [1933-1934]; (TS, 12 p.) (Folder 70.9)
    - College theme: "Gerard Manley Hopkins" [published in The Vassar Review, February 1934], [approximately 1934 Feb]; (TS, 11 p.) (Folder 70.10)
  - Notes from courses after Vassar
    - Course notes: Baroque Art, New York University, [1934 Sep]; (TS, MS, 81 p.) (Folder 71.1)
    - Course notes: Geometry, New School for Social Research [?], [1934-1935?]; (MS, 9 p.) (Folder 71.2)
    - Course notes: Early Keyboard Music, taught by Ralph Kirkpatrick, [1934-1935?]; (MS, 8 p.) (Folder 71.3)
  - Notes about Teaching and Readings
    - Lecture Notes, 1977; (TS, 5 p.) (Folder 71.4)
    - Lecture Notes, undated; (MS, 3 p.) (Folder 71.5)
    - College Teaching Notes, Exams, 1972-1975, undated; (TS, MS, 80 p.) (Folder 71.6)
    - Teaching Observations, 1976; (TS, 11 p.) (Folder 71.7)
    - Notes about Poetry Readings, 1972-1973, 1977, undated; (MS, TS, 21 p.) (Folder 71.8)
  - Notes and notebooks of drafts, dreams. and other observations
    - Drafts, Sonnets: Flags and Banners; Coxcomb;Washington as a Surveyor; The Map; The Reunion; Wading at Wellfleet; Three Poems; the Gentleman of Shallot; Dreams they Forgot; Bicyclists; The Water Fall; The Man-Moth; Up the Facades; Valentine V; Travel; On the Island; Coney Island, 1934-1936 (Folder 72.1)
    - Drafts: The Proper Tears; Digs at Relatives; In a Room; Song; The Third Dimension; Remarks on Auden; Prince Mannerly; The Death of a marshmallow; Sea Notes; Relatives; Luxembourg Gardens, 1934-1936 (Folder 72.2)
    - [Recorded Observations: begins with "Cuttyhunk, July 1934."], 1934-1937 (Folder 72.3)
    - Translations of Aristophanes’ The Birds (pp. 1-35, 56-59), 1933-1934, 1954 (Folder 72.4)
      Translations of Aristophanes’ The Birds — See also Folder 53.1
    - Minha Vida de Menina (The Diary of Helena Morley), 1954 (Folder 72.4)
    - Miscellaneous Notes, [1948-1950] (Folder 72.5)
    - Miscellaneous Notes, [1951] (Folder 72.6)
    - Miscellaneous Notes and Observations, 1951 (Folder 72.7)
    - Minha Vida de Menina [Beginning of Bishop's translation of The Diary of "Helena Morley"], [1954] (Folder 73.1)
    - Drafts: Question of Travel; Filling Station; Armadillo; Problems of Travel; list of poems, list of stories; The Spun-Sugar Man; Station #2; St. John's Day; The Owl's Nest; Poem for a Child; Judy; Exchanging Hats, 1955-1956 (Folder 73.2)
    - Drafts: Brasil 1959; On the x-ray of an 8-months Foetus; Overtaking a Funeral; Squibb Building, 17th Floor; Mimoso, Near Death; Naked Dog, the Dog; unfinished poems (Folder 73.3)
    - Drafts: Sandpiper; Miami; The Blue Chairs, Gysophilia, 1961-1962 (Folder 73.4)
    - Ouro Prêto, miscellaneous notes, 1961-1965 (Folder 73.5)
    - Miscellaneous Notes, 1962-1964 (Folder 73.6)
    - Drafts: The Table; Trip to the Interior; O Barril Mágico; After Bonnard; Translations, 1965 (Folder 73.7)
    - Brazil Notes, 1969 (Folder 73.8)
    - Drafts: Late Sleepers; This is Not a Bill; Just North of Boston; Florida Revisited, 1974-1977 (Folder 73.9)
    - Unused notebook (Folder 73.10)
    - To be used for Brazil notes, undated (Folder 74.1)
    - Hospital notes, undated (Folder 74.2)
    - Miscellaneous notes; Drafts: Sestina; A Ride on the Swan-Boats; Manuelzinho, undated (Folder 74.3)
    - Miscellaneous notes; Drafts: Old Home at Night; 6 A.M., undated (Folder 74.4)
    - Unfinished Poems, undated (Folder 74.5)
    - Drafts: A Little About Brazil; Rainy Day Rio, Epithalamium; Mountains Complain Continuously, undated (Folder 74.6)
    - Drafts: For Manuel Bandeira; Miscellaneous Notes, undated (Folder 74.7)
    - Miscellaneous Notes, undated (Folder 74.8)
    - Drafts: St. James; Look Up; June 13th; Homesickness; The Clock in the Custom House Tower; North Haven, undated (Folder 74.9)
    - Miscellaneous notes, unfinished poems, [undated] (Folder 74.10)
    - Reading Notes, New York Public Library, 1934-1935; (MS, 41 p.) (Folder 74.11)
    - Notes: "Blues, etc. - [Key] [West], 1938?-1939?; (MS, 12 p.) (Folder 74.12)
    - Notes, Portuguese, undated; (MS, TS, 12 p.) (Folder 74.13)
    - Notes for the Dickinson/ Hopkins Poem, undated; (TS, 3 p.) (Folder 74.14)
    - Miscellaneous note re: Bishop's paintings, with handwritten annotations not in Elizabeth Bishop's hand], undated; (TS, 1 p.) (Folder 74.15)
  - Notes and notebooks of drafts, dreams, etc. (purchased from Nemer)
    - Enclosures removed from notebook in 75.3: [Incomplete list] In the Golden Early Morning; Full Moon, Key West; The Second Plague [2 photos removed and placed in photograph series] 18 p. (Folder 75.1)
    - Enclosures removed from notebook in 75.4: Apologia; Job; It Is Marvellous to Wake Up Together...; Mrs. Newbold's Visitor; obituary clippings of Elizabeth Bishop's father;miscellanea [2 photos removed and placed in photograph series] 10 items (Folder 75.2)
    - Key West Notebook I, pp. 1-100: (Drafts and miscellaneous notes) [incomplete list]: Gone?; Song; Current Dreams?; Bolita; The Slot Machine; Solemn Mood; The Dying Dolphin; King St.; V-Day; The Factory; Individual Hopes; A Trip; A Candle in the Shape of a Snowman; The White Snow; Blue Postman (Folder 75.3a)
    - Key West Notebook I, pp. 101-205: (Drafts and miscellaneous notes) [incomplete list]: The Museum; Beautiful Prince Edward Island; Low Tide, Ragged Islands; 5 Islands, 5 Houses; Half Moon Hotel, Coney Island, September 28th; New Year's 1947; The Traveler to Rome; My Dearest...; Halifax; Dear Dr. Foster; Wild Flowers; The Strike of Love; Sudden Squall; Faustina II; 2 Negroes on Bicycles; The Lute Musicians; The Snowy Owl [Enclosures removed and placed in 75.1] (Folder 75.3b)
    - Key West Notebook II, pp. 1-125: (Drafts and miscellaneous notes) [incomplete list]: The Balloon and the Hard [?]; Grandmother's Glass Eye; Dear --:; Dream, February 4th; Denials; Love in Luna Park; The Sand-piper's Revenge; The Battle Scene; Waiting for the Mail; Numero Deus Impare Gaudet; Dreams; Embarrassment; Villanelle; Lullabye for the Cat; Hotels and Last Resorts; Dream; Letter to a Newspaper; Flourishes; The Sandman's House; Ireland; Quai d'Orleans; Victoria; Embarrassment and Tact; Job's Comforters; Dream, October 23rd; The Second Plague; Dream, January 2; The Mother-beaters; Money; At Mrs. Pindar's; Allegory rather than Conceit; In the Library (Folder 75.4a)
    - Key West Notebook II, pp. 126-242: (Drafts and miscellaneous notes) [incomplete list]: Thoughts from Here; Pansies; The Doom, the Explanation; Dream; O Angel Guardian; Leaves of the Calladium; Charcoal-Burners; After the Rain: K.W.; Fiddler-Bar; Incredibility; At Mrs. Pindar's; The Northern Hotel; Murray Hill Hotel; Firehand; Sonnet; Edgar Allan Poe and the Juke Box; Napoleon and Hannibal; Charlemagne; Key West; Water-fall; War in Queens; In the Dunes; The Street by the Cemetery; Florida Deserter; For A.B.; Baby's Grave, Key West; The Salesman's Evening; Edgar Allan Poe and the Juke-Box [Enclosures removed and placed in 75.2] (Folder 75.4b)
    - Enclosures removed from notebook in 76.2: [incomplete list]: The World after the [?]; For MDEA; The Fortunate Traveller; Tierra del Fuego; An Old Philosopher; Now I Am Adjusted to Reality...; Walk Around Here and Now --21 p. (Folder 76.1)
    - Key West Notebook (Drafts and miscellaneous notes) [incomplete list]: January, 611 Frances St.; February - 1949 Port-au-Prince; P.P.H.; Crossing the Equator; Thanksgiving Day 22nd; Todos of Santos; Samambaia, November 10th, 1952; Aleijadinho - the little cripple; March, 1954 (Folder 76.2)
    - Telephone/address book (Folder 76.3)
- SERIES VIII. TRAVEL JOURNALS AND NOTES
  - Notes — Newfoundland Trip, 1932; (TS, MS, 13 p.) (Folder 77.1)
  - Travel Journal, 1937 May-1938 Feb (Folder 77.2)
  - Travel Journal, 1938 Mar-1942 Sep (Folder 77.3)
  - Travel Journal, 1961 (Folder 77.5)
  - Travel Journal — Norway Trip, 1972 (Folder 77.6)
  - Travel Journal — "North Haven - July, August 1978..." (Folder 121.1)
  - Loose items removed from "North Haven" journal, (2 poetry fragments, 1 Harvard University Library circulation card) (Folder 121.2)
  - Travel journal — Trip to Greece, 1979 (Folder 121.3)
  - Loose items removed from Greece journal, (1 photo, 1 note about clouds, 1 credit card slip, 1 pressed poppy) (Folder 121.4)
- SERIES IX. DIARIES, DATEBOOKS AND CALENDARS
  - Diary ("Just about my worst, so far -"), 1950 (Folder 77.4)
  - Datebook, 1951 (Folder 78.1)
  - Datebook, 1957 (Folder 78.2)
  - Datebook, 1959 (Folder 78.3)
  - Datebook, 1970 (Folder 120.1)
  - Datebook, 1971-1972 (Folder 120.2)
  - Datebook, 1972-1973 (Folder 120.3)
  - Datebook, 1973-1974 (Folder 120.4)
  - Datebook, 1975 (Folder 120.5)
  - Datebook, 1977 (Folder 120.6)
  - Datebook, 1978 (Folder 120.7)
  - Calendar, 1974 Feb-Dec (Folder 106.3)
- SERIES X. BIOGRAPHICAL AND FAMILY DATA
  - Elizabeth Bishop — Birth certificate, 1919 Aug 28 (Folder 122.1)
  - Elizabeth Bishop — Baby book, 1910- (Folder 113.1)
  - Elizabeth Bishop — Baby book – inserts, 1903, 1909; (3 greeting cards, 2 pages from a photo album, and 12 loose photos) (Folder 113.2)
  - Elizabeth Bishop — curriculum vitae and chronology (Folder 122.5)
  - Elizabeth Bishop — Index cards of Bishop’s personal library at Lewis Wharf (Office card catalog)
  - Elizabeth Bishop — Address Book, approximately 1964 (Folder 120.8)
  - Elizabeth Bishop — Address Book, approximately 1967-1968 (Folder 120.9)
  - Elizabeth Bishop — Address Book — Brazil, undated (Folder 120.10)
  - Elizabeth Bishop — Address Book, undated (Folder 120.11)
  - Elizabeth Bishop — Passport, 1935-1937 (Folder 120.12)
  - Elizabeth Bishop — Passport, 1941-1942 (Folder 120.13)
  - Elizabeth Bishop — Passport, 1961-1971 (Folder 120.14)
  - Elizabeth Bishop — Passport, 1966-1971 (Folder 120.15)
  - Elizabeth Bishop — Passport, 1972-1976 (Folder 120.16)
  - Elizabeth Bishop — Passport, 1979 (Folder 120.17)
  - Elizabeth Bishop — Vaccine certificate, 1979 May 15 (Folder 120.18)
  - Elizabeth Bishop — Brazilian I.D. card, 1967 (Folder 120.19)
  - Bishop Family — Wedding invitation: Gertrude Boomer to Wm. Bishop; letter from Mrs. Bishop to Mrs Boomer, 1908, 1912; (2 p.) (Folder 78.4)
  - Bishop Family — Genealogy (Folder 78.5)
  - Morris Bishop — Appendix C from Champlain: The Life of Fortitude, undated; (TS, 5 p.) (Folder 78.6)
  - Alice Methfessel — Miscellaneous material, (1 greeting card, 1 note, 1 receipt) (Folder 115.17)
  - Flavio Eduardo de Macedo Soares Regis — re: application to Harvard, 1963-1964; (6 p.) (Folder 78.8)
  - Lota de Macedo Soares — Nationality card, driver's license, postcard of Lota's park, 1928, 1938, undated (Folder 78.7)
  - Lota de Macedo Soares — Funeral arrangements, 1967 (Folder 122.12)
  - Lota de Macedo Soares — Brazilian articles about her death, sent to Elizabeth Bishop by Stella Pereira, 1967 Sep; (2 clippings (Folder 122.13)
  - Lota de Macedo Soares — Will and other documents relating to her estate, 1967-1969, undated (Folder 122.14)
  - Lota de Macedo Soares — Memorial notice for her father, [1967] (Folder 122.15)
  - Lota de Macedo Soares — Miscellaneous material (Folder 122.16)
  - Map of Samambaia featuring the Soares/Bishop home (Folder 122.17)
- SERIES XI. WORKS BY OTHERS
  - Translations of Bishop works by others
    - French Translations, by LaFeuille, undated; (TS (copy), 117 p. with Elizabeth Bishop's corrections) (Folder 79.1)
    - Spanish Translations, by Jaime Manrique, undated; (TS, 14 p.) (Folder 79.2)
    - Spanish Translations, by Octavio Paz, undated; (TS, 13 p.) (Folder 79.3)
    - Spanish Translations: Brasil. January 1, 1502, by Aomero Icaza Sanchez, undated; (TS, 2 p.) (Folder 79.4)
    - Five Flights Up - translation into the Portuguese by Emanuel Brasil, undated; (1 annotated photocopy of a TS) (Folder 121.9)
  - Works about Elizabeth Bishop by others
    - Anonymous Essays about E. Bishop, undated; (TS (copies), 21 p.) (Folder 79.5)
    - Ashbery, John: "Elizabeth Bishop,", undated; (TS (copy), 3 p.) (Folder 79.6)
    - Brown, Ashley: "Elizabeth Bishop as Translator,", undated; (TS, 8 p.) (Folder 79.7)
    - Chittick, V. L. O.: "Nomination Seconded,", [approximately 1967 Feb]; (TS, 9 p. with letter from C. L. Bennet) (Folder 79.8)
    - Frankenberg, Lloyd: "Poetry's Bright New Star" [review of North and South], undated; (TS (carbon), 3 p.) (Folder 79.9)
    - Gordon, Lois: "Elizabeth Bishop,", undated; (TS (copy), 4 p.) (Folder 79.10)
    - Jordao, Vera Pacheco: "Aos Amigos da Poesia,", undated; (TS (carbon), 2 p.) (Folder 79.11)
    - Kalstone, David: "Reading Contemporary Poetry,", undated; (TS (copy), 31 p.) (Folder 79.12)
    - MacMahon, Candace: [Preliminary Bishop Bibliography], [1979]; (TS, 48 p. with 2 p. TS notes by E. Bishop) (Folder 79.13)
    - McMahon, Eileen: [Interview with Elizabeth Bishop], undated; (TS, 7 p.) (Folder 79.14)
    - Meredith, William: "An Invitation to Miss Bishop,", 1974; (TS (carbon) 3 p.) (Folder 79.15)
    - Mizener, Arthur: "Elizabeth Bishop..." [review of North and South], undated; (TS (carbon), 4 p.) (Folder 80.1)
    - Mortimer, Penelope: "Elizabeth Bishop's Prose,", undated; (TS (carbon), 5 p.) (Folder 80.2)
    - Paz, Octavio: [Essay about E. Bishop], undated; (TS, 3 p. with note by Elizabeth Bishop) (Folder 80.3)